<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 17:04:09 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 17:04:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wrangling Jekyll for Blogging</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Good news! I’ve finally mastered the fine art of using Jekyll to add a blog to my wonderful site. It actually wasn’t that difficult. Most of my time was spent exploring the deep, dark caverns around properly setting a base_url until I just said “FUCK IT” and went with my root domain, which I’ll swap out for local development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, it’s actually way easier than I thought it would be. I have a long-standing, nasty habit of building very simple tasks up to be monumental undertakings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, I plan to spend some time this weekend porting all of my old blog posts over from blogspot, then fully migrating everything here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Styling is still pretty boilerplate, but I’ll get to that. The main thing is the blog is up, it works, and it’s easier than I thought it would be. BONUS: made quite a bit of improvement with the layout, updating templates to be more templatey, DRYing shit up every, son.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 15:04:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2015/03/06/wrangling-jekyll-for-blogging.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2015/03/06/wrangling-jekyll-for-blogging.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I Did in February; Or, the Nightmare of Copy Editing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I came out of February having read three more books, having written thousands of words, and discovered something about myself and how much I love copy editing. &lt;strong&gt;SPOILER ALERT:&lt;/strong&gt; not at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Wrote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that I have to go back through my Twitter feed for notes on what I wrote in any given month. I finished up one short story, began an edit of the first story I finished in January, and started another story. Cross-referencing Twitter in this way is dumb, so I’ve added another sheet to my progress tracking spreadsheet. That spreadsheet’s getting pretty fat, man. I’ve got lots of progress I want to track!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That old saying “Writers like having written” is hot, boiling garbage. I like writing, and I spent several blissful mornings drinking &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blackheartenterprises.com/&quot;&gt;cold, black coffee&lt;/a&gt; and banging out a story. I sat down with a printed copy of my first draft, red pen in hand, only to find editing my own writing a chore beyond imagining. I’d rather have been writing something new. I’d rather have been anywhere but editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Just finish one pass. Just one first edit, then you can start another story.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the credo I lived by for over a week. I kept finding reasons not to edit my first draft. Somehow I made it through, though I’m still about halfway through a second pass. I blamed various interferences - a lack of good red pens, or discomfort in my computer chair when I sat down to edit. Just a string of shitty excuses to keep myself from doing the work that I knew needed to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll need to find a way to weasel editing into my daily routine. Some system for editing, a clever way to trick myself into it. Maybe I edit for 20 minutes every evening. After buying some new red pens, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Elements-Style-Fourth-Edition/dp/020530902X&quot;&gt;The Elements of Style&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Strunk and White&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m what? 90% sure I’ve read this before? I’m reasonably certain this was required reading in one of my early journalism classes. Either way, the refresher was wonderful. This old bastard dates back to 1918, and the advice contained still feels fresh, nearly a century later. Strunk has no patience for sloppy writing, and I love that he calls poorly constructed sentences “indefensible”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Permission-Marketing-Turning-Strangers-Customers/dp/0684856360&quot;&gt;Permission Marketing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Seth Godin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s tempting to just put all of the other marketing books I’m planning to read this year on hold until I’ve worked through Godin’s entire library. Permission Marketing is an old book (first published in 1999) and it shows its age when Godin writes about specific companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the specifics don’t matter. He writes with self-effacing humor and a natural curiosity that makes discussion of otherwise dry, technical case studies a true pleasure to read. I’ve read a couple of his other books (The Dip, All Marketers are Liars) and he’s never disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Persuasive-Online-Copywriting-Take-Words/dp/0971476993/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1425703297&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=persuasive+online+copywriting&quot;&gt;Persuasive Online Coypwriting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Bryan Eisenberg, Jeffrey Eisenberg, Lisa T. Davis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve kind of been doing a “thing” with dated online marketing books. This one was good, not as enjoyable to read as Permission Marketing, but reinforcing modern standards of online copywriting: focus on benefits, measure conversions, keep your eye on the fucking ball. Your visitors don’t give a shit about you. They give a shit about what you can do for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I Felt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;February felt pretty good. I didn’t get as much writing done as I’d have liked (see that week spent copy editing) and I’ve discovered I dislike editing my work. This is almost certainly a “thing” for at least some set of writers, and I need to get over it. I plan to implement a new system for editing in March, considering I’ve got a handful of first drafts under my belt now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first pass of my first story was painful, but productive. I cut out a lot of shit, removed tons of ideas that weren’t working and didn’t go anywhere, but I got bogged down in the second pass. It might be time for another, just to take what I have now, print it out again, and start over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I’ll pass it off to Miss Lady for further editing, and that idea is terrifying. Writing a story is one thing, but letting someone else read what I’ve written? AIEEEEEEE&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/learning/2015/03/02/nightmare-of-copy-editing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning/2015/03/02/nightmare-of-copy-editing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I Did in January: My Super Rad Writing System</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Wrote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using my super rad writing system (500 words per day, and 1,000 words per day on the weekends) I’ve written rough drafts for two short stories and I’m most of the way through a third. It’s hard to calculate just how far I am into this third story. I’ve discovered something interesting about writing fiction - it doesn’t always go according to plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve scoffed at people who write without an outline (and I still do, it’s MADNESS) but I have been surprised more than once at events that unfold while I’m writing. A character will make a surprise trip to a butcher’s shop, and it all feels very natural even though I didn’t plan on it in my rough outline before sitting down to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly those hilarious gems from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nanowrimo_txt&quot;&gt;@nanowrimo_txt&lt;/a&gt; make more sense. But not much more - let’s not get crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote the first story using textedit, using folders and a ton of text files. This was not ideal, and I knew it, but it’s how I did it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fully planned to switch to either &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ulyssesapp.com/&quot;&gt;Ulysses&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener.php&quot;&gt;Scrivener&lt;/a&gt; for the next story. I downloaded trials for both, but ended up using &lt;a href=&quot;https://evernote.com/&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; when it came time to sit down and write, at the recommendation of my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://mileszs.com/&quot;&gt;Miles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Sure,”&lt;/em&gt; I thought. &lt;em&gt;“This works fine. Better than a folder full of disorganized and loosely connected text files. But I’ll give one of the other apps a shot on the next story.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope. Didn’t happen. I’m still sticking with Evernote. It’s got the feature set I want (easy to organize stories and groups of stories, cloud sync, accessible from any device I can log into) without the bloat of something like Scrivener. Protip: If I have to go through a 400-step tutorial to use your writing software, I am not going to use your writing software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ulysses is more light weight and seemed like a reasonable alternative, but I find it to be comparable in feature and usage to Evernote, so I don’t have a compelling reason to switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke a bit about my writing system in my last post, but I haven’t mentioned my reading system. In short, I want to read three books per month: one book on writing, one book on copywriting, and one book on marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I read in January:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Writing-10th-Anniversary-Memoir-Craft/dp/1439156816/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1425703880&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=on+writing&quot;&gt;On Writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Stephen King&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Writing was a singular joy to read, and I wish I’d read it a decade ago. Stephen King is the reason I wanted to be an author as a child, and this book was the perfect combination of memoir and practical writing advice from a master of the genre. Bonus: tons of interesting insights into horror stories I read in high school, how he wrote them, where he was when he wrote them, and the impact they had on his family’s lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Ogilvy-Advertising-David/dp/039472903X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1425703914&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=ogilvy+on+advertising&quot;&gt;Ogilvy on Advertising&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by David Ogilvy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ogilvy on Advertising and The Copywriter’s Handbook were less enjoyable to read, but full of practical information. I was surprised to find Ogilvy on Advertising felt less dated than The Copywriter’s Handbook, likely because Ogilvy focused less on specifics than Bly did. Ogilvy’s relentless focus on provable, measureable results is fascinating. He was talking about data-driven marketing (a common enough practice in 2015) way back in the mid-1980s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Copywriters-Handbook-Step---Step-Writing/dp/0805078045/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1425704153&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=copywriter%27s+handbook&quot;&gt;The Copywriter’s Handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Robert Bly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The copy of The Copywriter’s Handbook I read had a new section on writing for the web (this version was published in 2005 or so) and felt hilariously dated in 2015. Tons of mentions of “e-zines”, for example, although the strategies Bly wrote about in 2005 still apply today (collecting emails, running drip campaigns, selling with benefits). Again, much like Ogilvy: work on something you can measure. Try new approaches, measure the results, get better over time. Solid, practical advice for any marketer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common thread I noticed in all three of these books is each writer takes a practical, craftsman-like approach to writing. These aren’t flowery authors. They write about the “craft” of writing, not the “art”, which appeals to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thoughts on My Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One month in and I’m feeling good about these systems. I’ve gotten a lot more done in a single month than I typically do, and that persistent, nagging feeling that I should be using my spare time more productively has all but vanished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve already thought of ways to extend and improve these systems - bumping up my word count, for example, and keeping notes on the book I’m reading as I read it. This would help with summary blog posts at the end of the month, and I’d be able to talk about a book I read three weeks ago with more salient points than “It was good, I liked it”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, off to a good start. Feels good to talk about things I’ve done, not things I plan to do. I feel less pressure to keep a promise I’ve made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this and you’ve got book recommendations, writing tips or anything else you’d like to rap about, I’m all ears. You’ve been on the internet before. You know how to leave a comment on a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/learning/2015/02/01/super-rad-writing-system.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning/2015/02/01/super-rad-writing-system.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>500 Words a Day</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been writing a lot lately. And reading a lot lately. And reading about writing a lot lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, I don’t like goals. Goals are fine for one-off tasks I want to accomplish (“I want to write a book this year”) but I find that goals tend to be demoralizing when I fail to meet them in time, and tend to make me complacent and lazy when I do meet them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Systems are better. I said I’ve been writing a lot lately. The current system I’m using is 500 words per day, 1,000 words a day during weekends. And it’s going well. I have days that it’s a struggle to get started, and I have days that it’s a struggle to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished a short story last week. The second short story I’ve ever finished in my entire life! It clocked in at 10,673 words (btw I totally checked my Twitter feed for that stat). Pretty chunky. This is a fat little story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently letting it sit for a couple of weeks before I go back in to edit. There’s a ton of fat to trim, and Stephen King’s advice from On Writing (fantastic read, not apologizing for these asides either) is to cut the rough draft by 10%. I’m no mathy, but that means 1,067 words have to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s two whole mornings of writing! Just &lt;strong&gt;WASTED!&lt;/strong&gt; What are you DOING, &lt;strong&gt;MAN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should note that blogging doesn’t count for my daily goal. I love blogging (and I’ve got the derelict LiveJournal account to prove it) but when I say “write 500 words” I mean 500 words of something I consider to be valuable in the long term. Working on a short story counts. Working on a novel would count (though I don’t think I’ve got the sack for a novel).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should take like one second and emphasize how good it feels to be writing again. I’ve wanted to be a writer since I can remember, and the last time I tried my hand at fiction was back in 2009, maybe 2010. That was the first short story I finished, by the way, and don’t think I don’t have plans for that little mess. &lt;strong&gt;BECAUSE I DO.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS I know I said blogging doesn’t count, and it doesn’t. Not for my daily goal. But it still counts. It’s a bonus. It’s a good way to keep me on track with what I want to do, and it’s a good way to track what I’ve done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging is a great outlet for talking to friends and strangers about something that’s important to me, but I don’t make much time to talk about: writing. Some other good advice from Stephen King: “If you can do it for joy, you can do it forever.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been like coming home. What? You didn’t know I was sentimental? Shit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/learning/2015/01/20/500-words-a-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning/2015/01/20/500-words-a-day.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Producing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not the biggest fan of LifeHacker as a platform for content. Most of the articles I run across are boring, click-bait listicles with no substance. More fluff in a sea of bullshit content marketing. This isn’t to say I think all content marketing is bullshit - I actually love well written, useful content marketing. But content marketing is the thing right now, and most of it is bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, we don’t choose the things that move us, and you can find inspirato in the most unlikely of places. I found this article a while back:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5887345/start-every-day-as-a-producer-not-a-consumer&quot;&gt;Start Every Day as a Producer, Not a Consumer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tldr; it’s about starting the day off by making something. Clearing your mind of distractions and working on something productive, not checking Twitter, not checking your email. For me, this means writing, even if I’m just banging some early morning thoughts out on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clay Johnson’s selling his book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.informationdiet.com/blog/read/500-words-before-8am&quot;&gt;The Information Diet&lt;/a&gt; with this article. This doesn’t disgust me the way it might have when I was in college. Good for him - I applaud him for the hustle. He’s got good advice, and he should sell a book about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s set a benchmark of producing 500 words first thing in the morning. I don’t think hard word count goals are very useful to me. It seems like I’d be writing long after I felt I was done writing, just to hit that limit, and that goes against my goal of writing every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I want to write every day, not write a predetermined number of words every day. Secondly, I want to improve my ability to write, not my ability to consistently hit a word count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, it’s going well. I feel motivated, but motivation isn’t enough. Desire is what counts, and I’ve been sharpening my own desire to write, forcing that old bastard out of bed, and it’s like greeting my oldest friend after a long absence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/writing/2014/12/01/producing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/writing/2014/12/01/producing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Writing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“You have to get up in the morning and write like a drunk has to drink.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eleven years later, this is still the best advice on being a writer I’ve ever heard.  One of my photography professors from college gave us this advice, given to him by one of his professors back in the 60s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The 60s…it was a terrible time. You should’ve been there.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His follow up advice wasn’t as useful, but it’s also stuck with me. I can still picture the day I heard this quote: the first day of class of my first actual photography class, nervous and excited, listening to a pompous man wearing a scarf in mid August. I had a hard time understanding why he was giving this advice, but he eventually related it to photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That quote stuck with him, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted to be a writer - not just good at writing, but an author. You should see the notes I have for short stories, novellas, novels. Notes upon notes that I’ve been compiling and hoarding since I was 17. I went through and organized all of my old writing notes a few nights ago: text files with single sentences, rough outlines of short stories, folders full of notes that barely make any sense a decade after I wrote them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a lot of time lately thinking about how I choose to spend my time, and whether I could put my time to better use, and the most obvious answer (as always) is “Write more.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to make time for writing. And I’m trying to make time once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know that I need to get up first thing in the morning and bang out a thousand words (some more practical though less inspiration advice I’ve heard lately) but I absolutely want to get back in the habit of writing every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve written about this quote before, I’m sure of it. Eleven years later and it’s still banging around in my head, and I’ve had more than enough blogs over the years. But I’m less concerned about not repeating myself, and more concerned about getting back into the habit that’s brought me endless amounts of satisfaction since I was eight years old.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/writing/2014/11/29/on-writing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/writing/2014/11/29/on-writing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Twilight / Lost Boys Fanfiction, Part I</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Edward Cullen found himself alone with his thoughts one rainy spring night, and decided to go for a walk to calm his nerves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll be back before dawn,” he sighed, to no one in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Be careful, Edward,” said Carlisle, his vampire dad. “You’re very special to us, and we love you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, Edward,” sighed Esme, his vampire mom. “Do be careful. I don’t know what we’d do if we lost you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m always careful. I just…need some fresh air,” Edward said intently, a distant look in his eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carlisle and Esme exchanged a look, and Edward was out into the storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hard for Edward to know exactly how far he walked that night. He walked for a really long time. Edward’s thoughts were heavy, and depressing, and important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one interrupted his dark and brooding walk until shortly after midnight, when a single headlight flared suddenly into existence behind him. Edward kept walking forward, completely consumed by his brooding introspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The headlight came closer and closer, its horn cutting through the sound of the storm. Edward stopped in his tracks as the vehicle came closer and closer, blaring its horn, until it came to a rest just behind him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Well, look at this shit,” a familiar voice called from behind Edward. “What the fuck are you doing out in this storm, Eddie?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edward gritted his teeth, clenching his fists before turning around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His old friend David rested his arms on the handlebars of his idling dirt bike, leering at Edward. A beautiful brunette slouched on the seat behind David, pouting at Edward and clearly enjoying the scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello, David,” sighed Edward, deciding to ignore David’s obvious insult. “I haven’t seen you in–“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I like your hair, Eddie. What kind of mousse are you using these days?” interrupted David, his tone curious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edward looked at David, not sure if he was being made fun of or not. Still, he and David WERE friends before, and Edward decided to give him the benefit of the doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, it’s—“ he begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nah, never mind. I don’t give a shit,” said David, cutting Edward off before he can finish his sentence. “Listen, what are you doing later? Me and some of the guys are going to go out, have a few drinks. You know. Like we used to. You want to come along?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edward hesitated, not quite meeting David’s gaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s the matter, Eddie? Star’s going to bring some of her friends, too. Come on, it’ll be fun!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think so, David. I don’t do…that, anymore,” said Edward, attempting to turn away from the other vampire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This statement took David off guard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What? What do you mean? You don’t drink blood anymore?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, I do. Just…not human blood. We feed on animals. We’re vegetarians,” he says, looking away from the other vampire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, fucking gross. You can’t be serious. How can you do that, Eddie?” David made a retching sound, then cocked his head at an angle. He leaned forward on the seat of his dirt bike, wearing a look of utter confusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t want to be a monster, David. I don’t want to be like you,” said Edward, defiantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, I wouldn’t worry about that, Eddie.  You’re nothing like me. Not anymore, anyway.” At this, David fell silent for a moment, looking away from Edward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How long?” he asked, finally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?” replied Edward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How long since you’ve had human blood, you idiot,” David grinned, his ivory fangs dripping with venom, both literal and metaphorical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not in decades. Not since my…rebellion,” sighed Edward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David howled with laughter at this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, your REBELLION. I forgot about what a REBEL you were, back in the 30s!” he laughed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edward felt his hands clenching themselves into fists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shut up, David,” he said, mentally preparing himself for a fight. David was older, stronger and more dangerous, but Edward had had enough of his bullying. Edward was completely prepared to use his gift of telepathy to gain the upper hand in a physical confrontation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To his surprise, David simply fell silent once more. David looked away from Edward, and when he spoke again, there’s a wistful tone to his voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You used to be cool, man,” David said, finally, flipping his elegant blond mullet back over his shoulder. Spring rain poured down David’s leather jacket, and the vampire wore a look of hurt and disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edward brushed his rain soaked hair out of his eyes, looking at David in surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Really? You—“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nah, I’m just fucking with you,” the blonde vampire laughed, interrupting Edward once again. “You were always a fucking dork!” With this remark, David revved the engine of his dirt bike, whipping the bike around and splattering mud all over Edward’s best set of trousers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dark haired beauty seated behind David on his dirt bike turned, smiling slyly at Edward. Very carefully, Star put her middle finger in the air as she and David roar off into the night, accompanied by the mocking laughter of the blond vampire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With his enhanced senses, Edward was able to get a very good look at Star’s French manicure when she flipped him the bird. He felt an emptiness unlike anything he’s known in his nearly 70 years as a vampire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll never be cool,” he whispered, watching the fading taillights of David’s dirt bike roaring away into the night. Edward touched his face, not surprised to find wetness there. Was it the early spring rain? Or tears?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/writing/2014/01/04/twilight-lost-boys-part-one.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/writing/2014/01/04/twilight-lost-boys-part-one.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
