<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 23:45:45 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 23:45:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wrangling Jekyll for Blogging</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Good news! I’ve finally mastered the fine art of using Jekyll to add a blog to my wonderful site. It actually wasn’t that difficult. Most of my time was spent exploring the deep, dark caverns around properly setting a base_url until I just said “FUCK IT” and went with my root domain, which I’ll swap out for local development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, it’s actually way easier than I thought it would be. I have a long-standing, nasty habit of building very simple tasks up to be monumental undertakings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, I plan to spend some time this weekend porting all of my old blog posts over from blogspot, then fully migrating everything here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Styling is still pretty boilerplate, but I’ll get to that. The main thing is the blog is up, it works, and it’s easier than I thought it would be. BONUS: made quite a bit of improvement with the layout, updating templates to be more templatey, DRYing shit up every, son.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 15:04:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2015/03/06/wrangling-jekyll-for-blogging.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2015/03/06/wrangling-jekyll-for-blogging.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I Did in February; Or, the Nightmare of Copy Editing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I came out of February having read three more books, having written thousands of words, and discovered something about myself and how much I love copy editing. &lt;strong&gt;SPOILER ALERT:&lt;/strong&gt; not at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Wrote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that I have to go back through my Twitter feed for notes on what I wrote in any given month. I finished up one short story, began an edit of the first story I finished in January, and started another story. Cross-referencing Twitter in this way is dumb, so I’ve added another sheet to my progress tracking spreadsheet. That spreadsheet’s getting pretty fat, man. I’ve got lots of progress I want to track!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That old saying “Writers like having written” is hot, boiling garbage. I like writing, and I spent several blissful mornings drinking &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blackheartenterprises.com/&quot;&gt;cold, black coffee&lt;/a&gt; and banging out a story. I sat down with a printed copy of my first draft, red pen in hand, only to find editing my own writing a chore beyond imagining. I’d rather have been writing something new. I’d rather have been anywhere but editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Just finish one pass. Just one first edit, then you can start another story.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the credo I lived by for over a week. I kept finding reasons not to edit my first draft. Somehow I made it through, though I’m still about halfway through a second pass. I blamed various interferences - a lack of good red pens, or discomfort in my computer chair when I sat down to edit. Just a string of shitty excuses to keep myself from doing the work that I knew needed to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll need to find a way to weasel editing into my daily routine. Some system for editing, a clever way to trick myself into it. Maybe I edit for 20 minutes every evening. After buying some new red pens, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Elements-Style-Fourth-Edition/dp/020530902X&quot;&gt;The Elements of Style&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Strunk and White&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m what? 90% sure I’ve read this before? I’m reasonably certain this was required reading in one of my early journalism classes. Either way, the refresher was wonderful. This old bastard dates back to 1918, and the advice contained still feels fresh, nearly a century later. Strunk has no patience for sloppy writing, and I love that he calls poorly constructed sentences “indefensible”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Permission-Marketing-Turning-Strangers-Customers/dp/0684856360&quot;&gt;Permission Marketing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Seth Godin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s tempting to just put all of the other marketing books I’m planning to read this year on hold until I’ve worked through Godin’s entire library. Permission Marketing is an old book (first published in 1999) and it shows its age when Godin writes about specific companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the specifics don’t matter. He writes with self-effacing humor and a natural curiosity that makes discussion of otherwise dry, technical case studies a true pleasure to read. I’ve read a couple of his other books (The Dip, All Marketers are Liars) and he’s never disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Persuasive-Online-Copywriting-Take-Words/dp/0971476993/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1425703297&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=persuasive+online+copywriting&quot;&gt;Persuasive Online Coypwriting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Bryan Eisenberg, Jeffrey Eisenberg, Lisa T. Davis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve kind of been doing a “thing” with dated online marketing books. This one was good, not as enjoyable to read as Permission Marketing, but reinforcing modern standards of online copywriting: focus on benefits, measure conversions, keep your eye on the fucking ball. Your visitors don’t give a shit about you. They give a shit about what you can do for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I Felt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;February felt pretty good. I didn’t get as much writing done as I’d have liked (see that week spent copy editing) and I’ve discovered I dislike editing my work. This is almost certainly a “thing” for at least some set of writers, and I need to get over it. I plan to implement a new system for editing in March, considering I’ve got a handful of first drafts under my belt now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first pass of my first story was painful, but productive. I cut out a lot of shit, removed tons of ideas that weren’t working and didn’t go anywhere, but I got bogged down in the second pass. It might be time for another, just to take what I have now, print it out again, and start over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I’ll pass it off to Miss Lady for further editing, and that idea is terrifying. Writing a story is one thing, but letting someone else read what I’ve written? AIEEEEEEE&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/learning/2015/03/02/nightmare-of-copy-editing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning/2015/03/02/nightmare-of-copy-editing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
